hey guys welcome back so in this
particular session we are going to talk
about our live project now we have done
some work on this already in our
previous sessions uh so we have already
created our component folder which is
the vehicle insurance and that will
contain all our test cases modules uh
test case design and requirements
okay so we have created the first set of
test cases we already have all the
modules okay uh for all these pages and
then we have our test case design for
vehicle
insurance and then we have our template
as well okay uh which will basically
contain all the steps including the
pre-processing process and
postprocessing so I have already used
all the best practices until now to uh
design all of these different templates
test cage design uh
modules and uh folder structure for test
cases um and everything is as per the
best practices defined by trius so do
try to follow all of these uh when you
are designing or uh creating your test
cases test templates or test case design
right now we have also instantiated and
we have created four different types of
test cases from our test design one is a
straight through we have got two valid
uh scenarios and one invalid scenario
now all of this has got different sets
of data right and we have also put some
verification points uh in one of our
test cases so you can see a lot of
things have been covered already uh in
this particular
application now in terms of the end to
endend functionality coverage of this
particular application let's see how
much we have covered and what is left
and we will be covering the remaining
functionality
the automation of those
functionalities in this particular
session okay so let's go ahead and
execute this and this will give us an
idea of what has been covered until now
and what is still left
okay okay so we have covered until uh we
select an option from the price options
after entering all the data like the
vehicle insurance and product data and
based on the prices we verify everything
which is displayed on this table and
then we select that particular option
which we want to uh go ahead with okay
now from here on uh we have also seen
how you can U verify a few things on the
PDF using the PDF uh scan now we need to
integrate that functionality where we'll
do some verifications on the PDF after
is generated and then we click on next
okay and then we enter all this
information and then we click on send
and then we verify whether uh success
message is displayed so this is the
functionality which is left over uh in
this particular application and that is
what we are going to cover
okay so to start off let's create all
the modules which are required to cover
or to automate all of this functionality
right so let's go to our module section
and here we have got different pages as
you can see right um and we have got the
select price option uh module and here
we have just got the
table so we can rescan this module and
uh we can then uh also put the other
buttons which are available here or
links okay so let's go ahead and rescan
this
and here um I'm going to add the
download code link okay and also the
next
button and these are the things which I
requir from this module now do remember
it's a best practice to not add all the
controls on the page for your module uh
it is only recommended that you add the
controls which you are actually using in
your automation for to these particular
modules which you are saving okay that
that improves the performance and also
uh saves you a lot of uh space if you
are working on a large workspace
okay so this page is complete now uh and
if I go to the next page in the send
code okay so let me uh scan a new module
here
right so here uh what we are going to do
is we are going to go to the basic View
and I'm going to just select my fields
or controls which I want to scan
okay okay and the send button so these
are all the uh things which I need to
add okay there is just another thing uh
which I would like to add and that's the
confirmation
message so let me go till there okay uh
and we are going to use the user
name and
password and I'm I'm going to click on
send
right now we have to wait until that uh
screen
appears and then I'm going to scan this
particular skill
okay
so we can scan this okay control button
right and then I'm going to finish
screen and save it
close the
module right so that should create our
um module for send
code so there are two uh modules created
with uh the same name so I will change
this to confirmation message okay and
that's our um other module so we have
scanned all the modules now which are
required for our automation and now we
need to start automating from the point
where we left okay so here after uh
doing the price option verification on
the page okay so we are buffering some
values we are verifying some values in
this table and now we have to select a
particular option right so either we'll
select silver or gold or platinum or
ultimate right it depends on our test
data what we want to select but
depending on that we need to click on
one of these options and then we'll
download the code and then we'll click
on next so these are the three
operations which we have to do on this
page
okay so let's first uh create a folder
here and I'm going to say select price
option here
okay and uh here I'm going to then add
the price option
module so this is the
module right and uh now we need to
select one of these values okay now as I
said uh which value we are going to
select that completely depends on um
what is our data point right so we need
to have some data point here which will
tell us uh what we are going to select
right okay uh so here in the process uh
I'm going to add another attribute okay
and I'm going to name it price
option this will give me all the
different price
options and uh I'm going to create some
instances here like
silver
and
gold then
Platinum and ultimate okay so these are
the four
instances right uh so now um we want uh
different data points right so we want
to select different values basically for
different test cases so let me put this
uh or fill this randomly okay so make it
orthogonal so it will select some values
here so now uh we have got uh some price
option which we can select on different
test cases now depending on what we have
been selected here uh we will then come
here and we will select the price option
based on that particular value okay so
I'm going to put a condition on this
particular folder okay so let's come
here and process and price option
and for silver I'm going to put a
condition on this folder right so
this and uh Al this will be only for the
administrative valid option right so we
don't want it to run for invalid so I'm
going to keep the test data type here
and also add this condition
here okay
also uh coming back here I don't want to
make it an or condition actually it
should be and condition okay so if both
both the conditions are met then only it
will be uh selected or this will be run
okay so now coming here uh so let's
change this a little bit select price
option
silver okay
and this will remain the same so here
coming back uh I just want to click on
this
okay because uh this price option is
silver it is going to click on this okay
now similarly I need to create for gold
platinum and ultimate okay so what I'm
going to do is I'm going to create some
copies here and just going to change
based on the names okay so this will be
faster uh you can do the same way which
I showed for the first
instance but to do this little fast I am
doing it this way
okay and platinum and then I'm going to
make it
ultimate right um and let's change the
names here so gold
and
latinum and
ultimate okay so these are the different
price options and we need to change the
operation here for that option so
instead of
this so let me just uh disable this and
let me click
here similarly for
ultimate so do remember if you don't
disable this step uh if you have copied
paste uh this folders or steps right the
action mode is input still so if you
don't uh disable this it will still
accept uh expect a particular value uh
in this particular field okay so do
remember that
uh and then the last
one okay so that's that's now complete
now before we move forward Also let's
see uh whether the instances are
generated correctly based on these
conditions which we have put right so
based on the price of option which has
been selected for that particular test
case uh it should only have this
particular folder okay so for silver it
will have the silver not the other three
and similarly for gold Platinum ultimate
uh it should have just one folder okay
so that's the uh conditional uh steps
which we have put so let's go to our uh
template first let's check whether there
is any errors or not so click on check
template no errors now go to uh template
instance and reinstantiate instances
okay so now for a straight through we
have selected silver if you remember and
you see there just select price option
silver okay and then uh for uh this uh
valid one so it will just have one price
option not four price options so it is
gold and for similarly for this uh it is
platinum
right so as you can see
uh how I'm using the conditions with the
test case design uh including the
instances and attributes to basically
design my different scenarios right so
based on different test data my test
scenarios are designed um on that
particular test data so not one of my
test case instance has got the same data
right and that's very important because
we want to have the optimal number
number of test cases instead of all the
test cases testing with the same test
data okay so that's of no use so you
need to intelligently put conditions on
your different uh test uh TS or folders
in your template and uh your test case
template should uh have all those
conditions in place so that when you
instantiate it will generate a set of
unique test cases for you okay
now uh moving forward we need to add
some more operations into our template
so we have basically two more operations
uh download code and next now I don't
need to do a download code for now uh we
can see it later how we can integrate
the PDF comparison which we have already
done or the PDF verification uh into
this particular uh scenario but for now
let's just complete the whole scenario
so I'll be just clicking on next and
filling up the fields on the next page
and then basically submitting this
application so it's a end to end
scenario right so it's basically a
straightforward scenario okay or a
straight through scenario you can say
which all the uh basic things which an
application can do but then uh obviously
you can expand your uh test cases your
scenarios based on your user
requirements right so you can add many
things uh into this particular
application but the goal here is how you
can uh basically do a endtoend uh
scenario or project in tosa using all
the different components uh which are
present
okay so uh coming back here we already
have this module so what we are going to
do let's go to our template and here
inside every uh price option we have to
put this particular click button okay so
that uh it completes that particular
operation now I would not do it in the
same test step since it's like a uh next
test step uh on clicking on the next
button so what we'll do we'll again um
do a select price option module we'll
search for
that and here we are going to click on
that button okay so I will rename this
test step as click
next and here I'm going to click on the
next button okay
right so uh we also need to have this uh
this this test step in every folder
because depending on the price option uh
it will has to do that particular
operation also right and here as
well so that that completes uh our next
steps and then once we uh reach here
okay so we click on next and we reach
here now let's let's fill these details
and click on send okay so for that again
uh in the process let's create and the
folder here so we will name this send
code right so this is the send
code and now inside this I will add a
test step which is the send code
again okay and here we need to fill all
the details now okay so these details
will uh again you don't need to provide
static values here it should be coming
from your uh test design sheet okay so
all the values should be configured uh
no static values in your test case
right so let's go here into our design
sheet and now we are going to add some
more options here so let's add an
attribute called send
quote okay uh and inside this again
another
attribute and this time around I will
say
email okay and then
phone although we might not use this
attribute uh
username and password
confirm
password and comments okay so these are
all
the values which we need to enter on
this particular page and that's why I've
created all the different attributes now
I need to create some instances here as
well so um I'm going
to create some email addresses here
okay uh not necessary that I use um any
specific email but for now I will just
leave it
okay and then phone number as I said
it's not really mandatory right now it's
not a mandatory field so we can avoid it
for now and use a name I will say Qs
script right
password again and
instance and uh I can
[Music]
say test at 1 2 3 Ash
okay and confirm
password again the
same and comments for now we can leave
it okay so these are all our
attributes uh let me just
okay now we need to select some values
here so for now I will have the same
email address you can have different
email address but generally it is not
the case right but if you have got
different users uh you can have
different email addresses here for
different test cases but for now I will
just select the same values okay so
let's use
this and this
okay so that's all our values and now
let's go back to our
template okay and here um I have to use
those values now so let's do
this and let me go to the section
particular section and pull those values
which we
have okay
right uh so I need to pull the
attributes here I'm pulling
and
username
password okay confirm
password and comments and phone we can
add it later but these are all the
values
okay so now we have got all the values
which are coming from the test design
sheet for this particular page okay and
and I don't want to execute this again
for U invalid test cases because it
won't reach to this particular page
right so I'll put this condition
here right uh after this okay so we have
done this and we want to click on
send
right also what we have to do is we have
to wait for the confirmation message
right
so what we'll do here is let's add the
test step and confirmation
message okay so I'll put a weight on
here and I will
see if this um exists equals equals true
right so if this exists so that's the
confirmation meage message and let me
just check
here right um so yeah so if this exist
that means we have got our confirmation
message right and then um we can also
click on the okay button so that's our
final step
so I'm adding again this particular test
step this time
around I'm going to say click
okay and and here I will say verify
confirmation
message and here we are going to click
on okay
right okay so that's all our steps okay
so we have completed the whole
application now uh we have enter all the
details and click on send and then we'll
get the confirmation so we'll verify
that and we'll click on okay so it's an
end to endend um application right all
the scenarios all the pages are covered
all the fields are covered and at least
one straight through scenario is now
covered okay there could be more
scenarios as I said uh there could be
lots of scenarios depending on your
testing requirements right but once you
know the process you can always add
those scenarios back
okay so now uh final thing which is left
is to check for the template whether it
is still valid or not and then
reinstantiate our instances so that all
the new attributes and values are uh
displayed here so in the process now we
have an additional step for send quote
okay and it has got all the uh different
test step and their
values okay um so now uh it is just a
matter of running this particular test
cases okay so what we'll do uh first of
all let's try it in scratchbook and then
we can also run it from the execution
list okay so let me run this in
scratchbook so great everything was
successful you can see it waited for
that confirmation message and uh instead
of a static weight I used Dynamic weit
which is wait on method so it will wait
for that particular control on that page
no matter how much time it takes and
then uh it will click on okay now it's
not a live application so we cannot uh
it doesn't send an actual email to the
email address which we provide so we
cannot do that email verification part
but uh with tosa you can even do that
okay so either you do it through the UI
or if you have an API so if the API is
uh sending that particular uh email
message to that email address then you
even you can um integrate the apis into
this particular test case now we have
already seen how you can build your API
test case so you just need to uh
integrate it uh basically in the next
test steps you just add those API
scenarios here so that you can even
verify the email which which is going to
that particular email address so that
will be like a complete integration of
all the different components of your
application right and this is how you
can perform and endtoend scenario using
all the different components which is
test case designing uh the test case
template the template
instances and uh even requirements we
have already added few requirements
right and then the modules uh we have
added lots of modules in this for this
application and then uh finally the
execution right so we already have
different execution lists right and uh
if you're working on a real project you
will also have test events right so to
run this on a distributed execution so
on different agents okay so if you have
that kind of a setup you can even create
test events uh that is only available
with the multi-user workspace so uh once
that is there uh you can even run it
there
okay uh just to wrap this up okay uh for
this live project which we have
completed right now um what we can do is
we can come here okay so we can uh
synchronize this here uh and
here just just to make sure that uh it
has got all the changes from our uh
recent changes which we have done
okay so uh if I can run one of these
test
cases from an execution list it will
have the same results uh there's no
difference between scratchbook and
execution list it is just that it will
store the results uh in my execution
list okay so but to make sure that
everything is still working as expected
from the execution list uh I'm also
running get from the execution list
okay but uh you expect the same things
okay and uh the same results the only
part which I did not show uh was um you
clicking on that particular uh PDF
button and then uh extracting that PDF
uh scanning and PDF uh verification
which we have seen
separately um into this particular test
case okay so you can see here now the
execution list is storing the results so
you have got the result uh with the date
of execution and time uh the duration is
also there right so you can execute all
the execution uh lists which we have
created for all the different
scenarios and uh as I have explained
earlier uh you can use the print view
option to basically export this uh into
uh report right so you can use any
format uh into Excel uh into a PDF uh so
all the all the formats are here uh
whichever you want to use okay and if I
want to use uh Excel just for uh
reporting purpose I can export
it and I can save it
here okay and then it will open it in
Excel obviously it will uh require some
formatting which you can do on your own
okay but after that uh it will look
proper so this um you can even use it as
a reporting format and to provide
reports to your management right just
need to format a few lines here and
there and uh this report would be
perfect for you and you can always add
and remove columns from your execution
so that it will appear the same way in
your report okay so you can generate any
uh PDF any Excel report based on your
requirement that's that's how uh you uh
will work on a realtime scenario okay uh
just make sure you are using the correct
uh or you are using the best practices
whenever you are developing any
particular project or you're working on
any project always use a component
folder uh to store all your components
okay uh and create this execution
modules requirements test case design
test cases inside the component folder
so if you are working on a large project
or you're working on multiple projects
you can have multiple component folders
but uh make sure that uh you use that
because that's one of the best practice
and also it is easy to maintain okay and
then um a naming conventions uh you have
to use right uh make sure you are not
using any constant values in your test
cases you are always parameterizing it
so you can do it using test
configuration parameter or uh you can
use your test case design to basically
enter all the values you have to use
conditions uh in order to have separate
instances for different scenarios right
and uh this was our uh complete endtoend
uh life project